Lisa Yankey

lisayankey@gmail.com
317.522.6276
Noblesville, IN
https://lyankey.github.io/portfolio/
Github.portfolio.link
https://www.linkedin.com/in/lisa-yankey/

Career Summary:

Software Developer with strong problem-solving, logic, analysis, social-engineering, time-management, and communication skills. Immgiration lawyer since 2008. Full of ideas and energy. Goal-oriented producer who is able to work well independently or as part of a team. Accomplished professional with extensive education experience including e-learning, start-up and website design experience. Open to part-time and contract work.

Education:

- Eleven Fifty Academy, Software Development Immersive Learning Program, Indianapolis, IN, December 2020
 - 12-week immersive learning program for Software Development taught with industry-guided curriculum, realworld project-based learning, and 500+ hours of logged coding time and training
- Indiana University Robert H. McKinney School of Law, Juris Doctor, Law, Indiana, May 2008
- California State University Los Angeles, Teaching Credential, K-12 and Social Studies, 2002
- California Polytechnic State University San Luis Obispo, Bachelor of Science in Social Sciences (Social Engineering),
 December 1998

Competencies & Functional Skills:

Proven track record for solving complicated problems using logic and analysis. Social engineering, legal compliance, anticipation and management of client needs, high-energy, creativity, fast research, time-management, communication, and Agile methodology. Twenty years of experience in education at all levels, including home school, public school, graduate school, e-learning, and professional training.

Technical Skills:

Languages: C#, ASP.NET, MVC, HTML, CSS, familiarity with Python, Javascript/Ajax

CI/CD: Agile, Scrum, Git, pair programming

Testing Tools: Unit Testing

Databases: SQL Server, familiarity with Python libraries NumPy, MatPlotLib, SciKit Learn

HTTP methods, API development, stateless components, session validation, responsive web design,

Web Technologies: Wordpress, Responsive web design (Bootstrap), deployment to Azure

Frameworks Entity Framework, Wordpress

Reporting/Publishing Tableau, Adobe InDesign, Canva design,

Technical Projects:

- Science And Chow .Net website https://scienceandciaowebazure.azurewebsites.net/
 - Used .NET Framework, HTML 5, CSS 3, Javascript, and knowledge of human development and social engineering to build a concept full-stack website to teach science in an unschool environment. The concept uses Temptationbundling to blend cooking classes with science classes – "make science deliciously irresistible"
- My GitHub Portfolio https://lyankey.github.io/portfolio/
 - o Used HTML 5, CSS 3, Bootstrap 4, and jQuery to design & build my mobile-responsive portfolio website
- SpacePlace Rental App https://github.com/rdarku/SpacePlace
 - o Used .NET Framework, Git, and Agile methodology to work as a team to build this .NET back-end

Professional Experience:

Owner/Attorney, Yankey Law Firm, August 2012 - Present (not accepting new cases)

- Practiced immigration law
- Used logic, analysis, and fast research skills to work directly with clients and government bureaucracy to solve tough problems
- Interpreted laws to find creative solutions
- Built and ran professional website using WordPress
- Kept strict confidentiality
- Planned and delivered professional education
- Managed office and staff

- Communicated effectively in Spanish
- Developed and ran Wordpress website

Author/Writer/Speaker, Self-employed, August 2016 - Present

- Used research and communication skills to write informative and interesting articles and books for various audiences from laypersons to professionals
- Used technology skills to post articles, product reviews on blogs
- · Used online portals and interfaces to submit work, and to coordinate work with editor and team
- List of publications and speaking events available on request
- Developed and ran WordPress websites

Legislative Policy Adviser, IAHE Action, August 2016 - Present (volunteer)

Work with a team to monitor legislation for potential changes in the laws that could affect education

Owner LearningLawyer, October 2012 – November 2018

Project Scope: Developed and ran a WordPress website as a way to facilitate efficient mentoring for volunteers in the legal community

- Built WordPress website to handle registration of users, submission of documents, and distribution of documents
- Wrote legal policies

Instructor, Trine University, March 2013-March 2015

Taught an online graduate level course using Moodle, AdobeConnect, and DyKnow Solutions

Staff Attorney, Neighborhood Christian Legal Clinic, November 2008-August 2013

- Used logic, analysis, and fast research skills to work directly with clients and government bureaucracy to solve tough problems
- Used Adobe Captivate to create training materials for volunteer attorneys
- · Did community education, outreach, and continuing professional education for attorneys
- · Kept strict confidentiality
- Managed department staff

Teacher, Public Schools, July 2000-May 2007

- Used communication, interpersonal skills, and educational skills to teach
- Developed curriculum, chose curriculum

Technical Awards & Achievements:

Eleven Fifty Academy Core Value Award Recipient